Tom Martin

tpgmartin@gmail.com

+44 (0)7946 330544

tpgmartin.com

github.com/tpgmartin

linkedin.com/in/tpgmartin

twitter.com/tpgmartin

Profile

Consultant data scientist with previous commercial experience as a software engineer in companies ranging from startups to large e-commerce companies. Able to bring together experience from both fields to deliver impactful business solutions. Created projects using Python and related libraries, Tableau, AWS, and NoSQL technologies. Currently studying Data Science MSc, graduating in 2020.

Experience

Consultant Data Scientist

CybSafe, One Canada Square, London

Nov 2019 (current)

Data Scientist Apr 2019 - Nov 2019

Capita Employee Solutions, 65 Gresham Street, London

- Created probabilistic model to determine performance or markers using various marking strategies.
- Curated data sources and produced DataBricks notebooks for company reputational index.
- Created self-service Flask web app deployed on Microsoft Azure to identify payroll discrepancies, output as HTML presentation.
- Created pre-employment screening POC using Ethereum blockchain.

Data Scientist Nov 2017 - Mar 2019

Skills Matter, Finsbury Circus House, 10 South Place, London

- Initiated drive to become data-driven organisation, identifying KPIs with product teams. Creating visualisations and Tableau dashboards, integrations with Metabase and Slack.
- Identified customer segments using RFM analysis.
- Identified trending StackOverflow topics using exponentially weighted moving average/variance of tag usage.
- Created data pipeline, reading from multiple third-party data sources and writing to AWS redshift.
- Created Flask web app to view and summarise conference reviews.
 Use sentiment analysis to provide summaries of written reviews.
- Mentoring junior members of staff on using data analysis tools.

Software Engineer Dec 2014 - Nov 2017

OpenTable, Alphabeta Building, 14 -18 Finsbury Square, London

- Updated and maintained entire pipeline for promotions and offers, including database, online editor, APIs, frontend. Lead to full integration and support of offers across microsites.
- Created API to support multilingual translations of promotions, to enable seamless user experience regardless of domain or language
- Updated concierge website frontend, utilised GraphQL to streamline database access.
- Created mobile-first responsive frontend for international launches.

Developer May - Oct 2014

Modaventure, Google Campus, London

- Created frontend for contractor recruitment platform using AngularJS.

Public Speaking

- <u>The Why of Data-Driven Organisations</u>, Infiniteconf 2018, July 2018. A talk about the key motivating factors for a business aspiring to become "data-driven"
- Neural Networks from Scratch, Infiniteconf 2017, July 2017. An introduction to how artificial neural networks work, including their architecture and the gradient descent learning algorithm, with code samples.
- <u>The Brief on Developer Book Clubs</u>, London Web Standards, January 2017. A review of the motivations for and progress of a book club I initiated at OpenTable.
- <u>Progressive Web Applications</u>, Web Platform London, December 2016. A look at the key APIs behind progressive web apps: service workers, cache API, fetch API.

Courses

Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree

Udacity, online

Web Development Immersive

General Assembly, London

Education

Data Science MSc 2018 - 2020

City, University of London

Physics with Theoretical Physics MSci, First Class

Imperial College London

- Undergraduate Research Opportunities Programme (UROP) June - August 2011

Sep 2016 - Feb 2017

Dec 2013 - Mar 2014

2008 - 2012